Guide to the Ruth Barcan Marcus Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Subject files, 1940-2011; Series II
  - Church, Alonzo, 1984, undated (Box 18, Folder 12-14)
  - Cognitive, 1980-1981, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Cognitive development, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Cognitive psychology bibliography, Judy, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Cognitive science, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Cohen, Josh, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - College de France, 1981-1986 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Colloquium in philosophy, 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Committee on Special Programs, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Connectives, Undated (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Connectives, Logic, Undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Contemporary Western Philosophy in Translation, China, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Copyright law, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Cornell University Society for the Humanities, Advisory Board, 1980-1984 (Box 18, Folder 27-30)
  - Correction requests to citations and database entries, 2006-2008 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Council for Comparative Study of Culture, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Council for International Exchange of Scholars (CIES), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Council for Philosophical Studies, 1988-1994 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Crews, Frederick, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Crowell, Steven, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Cummins, Robert and Dale Gottlieb, "On An Argument for Truth-Functionality", 1972 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Czech Republic, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - D. Reidel Publishing Company, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - da Costa, Newton C. A., 1988-1990, undated (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Dart-computer, Undated (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Dartmouth College, 1980-1981, undated (Box 18, Folder 42-44)
  - Davidson, Donald, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Davis, Charles, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Decision problem, Undated (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - DeMorgan-Boole bibliography, Undated (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Dennett, Daniel
    - General, 1984 May (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - "Beyond Belief", Undated (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Deontic logic, Nuel Belnap, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - DeRose, Keith, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Derrida, Jacques, 1982-2008, undated (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
  - Derrida, Jacques, Paul de Man, and Martin Heidegger, 1984-1992, undated (Box 19, Folder 5-7)
  - Diacritics, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Diamond, Cora, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Dickie, George, 1975, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 10-11)
  - Dollard, J., Undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Donagan, Alan
    - "Causal and Semantic Elements in the Concept of Human Action", Undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Eulogy, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Doney, Willis, Undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Donnellan, K. S., 1972 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Donnellan, Peter, 1982-1983, 1998-1999 (Box 19, Folder 17-18)
  - Downey, C. E., "He Speaks for the Trees", 1975 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Duke University, 1987-1992 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Eaton, Marcia, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Edinburgh, fellowship, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Elizabethan Club, 1988-2001 (Box 19, Folder 23-24)
  - Emerson, 1992-1993, undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Empty domain, 1988 February (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - "Essential Attribution" critique, Undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Eveling, Stanley, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Farago, John, law articles, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Fédération Internationale des Sociétés de Philosophie (FISP)
    - General, 1978-1988 (Box 20, Folder 1-7)
    - 1983 Congress, 1980-1983 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Japan meeting, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Montreal, 1981-1983 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Feferman, Solomon, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Feinberg, Joel, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Feldman, Fred
    - General, 1973-1978, 1995, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 13-15)
    - "Kripke on the Identity Theory", 1974 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Feminism, 1987-1988 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Fern, Richard, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Films, Undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Findlay, J. N., Undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Fine, Kit, 1976-1978 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Fish, Stanley, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Fitch, Frederic
    - General, 1974-1988, undated (Box 20, Folder 23-26)
    - "The Absolute Consistency of ZF Set Theory", Undated (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Fest, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Schrift, 1973-1975 (Box 20, Folder 29-30)
  - Fogelin, Robert, 1976, 1981, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Føllesdal, Dagfinn, 2005, undated (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
  - Fondation Singer-Polignac, 1984-1985 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Formal Philosophy, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Frankfurt, Harry, 1978-1985, undated (Box 21, Folder 7-9)
  - Frege, Gottlob, "The Thought", Undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Fulbright, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Fulbright-Hays, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Garrett, Don, 1978, 1981, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Gay, Peter, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Geach, P. T., Undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Gendler, Tamar Szabo and Paul Bloom, 2007 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    E-mail discussing Josh Greene's theories.
  - Glymour, Clark, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Gorovitz, Samuel, 1982-1983, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Gottlieb, Dale, 1974-975 (Box 21, Folder 19-20)
  - Gould, Gordon, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Grant materials, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Grants and fellowships, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Greenspan, Patricia, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Grene, Marjorie Glicksman, Undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Grewe, Rudolf, 1974-1980, undated (Box 21, Folder 26-27)
  - Grossman, Reinhardt, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Grover, Dorothy, 1972-1975 (Box 21, Folder 29-30)
  - Guggenheim fellowship, 1953, 1963, 1977-1978, undated (Box 21, Folder 31-32)
  - "Guidebook for Publishing Philosophy", 1974 December (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Haack, Susan, 1990-1997, undated (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
  - Hacking, Ian, 1974, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Hall, Harrison, 1978-1982 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Hampshire College, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Hanover Congress, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Harman, Gilbert, 1976-1984 (Box 22, Folder 9-11)
  - Hartman, Geoffrey and Harry Frankfurt, 1984-1985 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Heidegger, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Heidelberger, Herbert, 1963-1964 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Hill, Charles, 2005-2010 (Box 22, Folder 15-16)
  - Hill, Claire, 1987-2007 (Box 22, Folder 17-18)
  - Hilpinen: notes on proof, Undated (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Hine, Daryl, Undated (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Hintikka, Jaakko, Undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Hintikka, Jaakko, festschrift, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Hirsch, E. D., Jr., "Meaning and Significance Re-Interpreted", 1984 May (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Hollander, John, 1975-1980 (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
  - Honderich, Ted, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Horowitz, Tamara, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Humanities Advisory Council minutes, 1983 January 27 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Humphreys, Paul, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 7-8)
  - Ikenberry, Stanley, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Interamerican Congress of Philosophy
    - General, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - American Philosophical Association (APA) support, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Internationale Akademie für Philosophie, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Institut Internationale de Philosophie (IIP)
    - General, 1974-1996 (Box 24, Folder 1-33)
    - Cooptation, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Expenses, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Israel, 1975-1977 (Box 25, Folder 3-5)
    - Membership, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Mexico, 1990-1991 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Nominations, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Oxford, Ricoeur, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Prague, 1938, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Université de Gand Assemblée, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - International Union of the History and Philosophy of Science (IUHPS)
    - Division of the Logic, Methodology, and Philosophy of Science (LMPS), 1978-1991 (Box 25, Folder 12-18)
    - United States National Committee (USNC), 1978-1983 (Box 25, Folder 19-20)
  - "Is Causality Physical?", Undated (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Israel, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Jacquette, Dale, 1987, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Jaeger, Robert, 1973-1982, undated (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
  - Job postings in philosophy, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Joint Boards of Permanent Officers procedures, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Joke, 1996-1997, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Jones, W. T., Undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Journal of Philosophical Logic, 1974, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 8-9)
  - Journal of Philosophy copyright regulations, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Jubien, Michael, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Kagan, Shelly, 2000, 2003 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Kalish, Donald, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Kant appointment, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Kaplan, David
    - General, 1967-1978 (Box 26, Folder 15-19)
    - Conference at Stanford, 1984-1986 (Box 26, Folder 20-21)
    - Conference at San Marino, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Demonstratives, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Descriptions and Quantification, Undated (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - "Logic of Demonstratives", Undated (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Quine
      - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - Criticism, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - Substitution and quantification, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Kaplanfest, 1988, 2001, undated (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Kenyon College, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Kingwell, Mark, review of Innocence and Experience in International Philosophical Quarterly, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Klibansky, Raymond, 1985-1998 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Kohlberg, Lawrence, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Kripke, Saul
    - General, 1976-2006 (Box 27, Folder 4-9)
    - Feminism, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Kripke's Puzzle, Undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Kuklick, Bruce, Undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Kvart, Igal, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Lacan, Jacques, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Lasch, Christopher, Undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Lauener, Henri, 1988-2006 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Lauener awards program, 2006, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Lauener Prize, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Lawyers, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Lear, Jonathan, 1987-1988 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Lear, Jonathan and Harry Frankfurt, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Leibniz (course), 1979 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Lemmon, E. J., "Deontic Logic and the Logic of Imperatives", 1964, 1967, undated (Box 27, Folder 23-24)
  - Letters to the editor, 1974-1988, undated (Box 27, Folder 25-26)
  - Levi, Isaac, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Lewis, C. I., 1947, 1960, 2001-2010 (Box 27, Folder 28-30)
  - Lewis, David, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Library, reserve lists and miscellaneous, 1974-1975 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Linsky, Leonard, 1976, undated (Box 27, Folder 33-34)
  - Lipset, Seymour, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Loar, Brian, "Social Content and Psychological Content", Undated (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Local 34 strike, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Logic Colloquium, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Loptson, Peter, "Cartesian Essentialism", 1974 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Lorimer, Linda, 1986, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Ludlow, Peter, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Lycan, William, 1985, 1993, undated (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1985-1994 (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
  - MacIntyre, Alasdair, 1988-1990 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - MacPherson, Brian, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Maddy, Penelope, "Logic and the Discursive Intellect", 1997 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Manning, Sylvia, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Manuscripts, 1958-1964 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Marino, Patricia, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Martin, Richard, critique, Undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    - General, 1975-1984 (Box 28, Folder 16-20)
    - Visiting Committee, Department of Linguistics and Philosophy, 1978-1984 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Matchette Foundation, 1971-1985 (Box 28, Folder 22-24)
  - Mathematical Reviews, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Maull, Nancy, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - McCall, Storrs, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - McCawley, Jim, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - McConnell, Terrance C., 1975-1980 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - McKenna, Amanda, Undated (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - McKinsey, J. C. C., truth, Undated (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Medical guidelines, 1981-1982 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - Mele, Alfred, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Metaphilosophy, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Michelson-Morley Centennial Celebration Symposium, Case Western Reserve University, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Miller, David Marshall, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - Miller, Hillis, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Millikan, Ruth, 1990-1995 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Modalities French translation, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - The Monist, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Mothersill, Mary, Century Club, 1980, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Nagel, Thomas, curriculum vitae, Undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Narveson, Jan, commentary on "Moral Dilemmas and Consistency", 1980 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities
    - General, 1975-1983 (Box 29, Folder 5-7)
    - Panel, 1984, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - National Humanities Center, 1981, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
  - National Science Foundation, 1971, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 11-12)
  - Neale, Stephen, 1995-2007 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Neiman, Susan, 1990-1992 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Nelson, Lowry, 1979, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - New York Philosophy Club, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - New York Times
    - General, 1986-1988 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Letter to the editor, 1982-1983, 2011 (Box 29, Folder 18-19)
  - New York University
    - Recognition, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Yearbook, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Nicholson, Susan, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Northwestern University, 1954-1955, undated (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Notes on papers, Undated (Box 29, Folder 24-25)
  - Nozick, Jeffrey, Undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Nozick, Robert, 1981-1982, undated (Box 29, Folder 27-28)
  - Nussbaum, Martha, 1984-1993 (Box 29, Folder 29-30)
  - Oakes, Colin, Circa 1996 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Obst, Linda Rosen, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Ohio State University College of Humanities Boards of Visitors, 1995-1996 (Box 30, Folder 3-4)
  - Original sin, Undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Overmann, Ronald, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 6-7)
  - Owens, David, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Oxford University Press
    - General, 1980-1982 (Box 30, Folder 9-11)
    - Appointment, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Delegate, 1991-1994 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Oxford Companion to Philosophy, 1992-1993 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Oxford Scholarship Online, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Oxford Visiting Fellowships, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Parikh, Rohit, 2007 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Paris conference, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Parsons, Charles, Undated (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Parsons, Terence, 1968-1969, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 20-21)
  - Pears, David, 1995, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1979-1994 (Box 30, Folder 23-26)
  - The Philosopher's Index, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Philosophy department rankings, Circa 1982 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Philosophy graduates employment survey, 1979-1980 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Philosophy of Science, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy of Science Association, 1977-1978 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy Research Archives, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1971-1972, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Piper, Adrian, 1993-1996 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Post-retirement search for positions, 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Presidential election humor, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Princeton
    - General, 1975-1984 (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
    - CODPEP, 1985, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Job offer refusal, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - "Proceedings of the 75th International Congress of Logic, Methodology, and Philosophy of Science", 1984 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Professional organizations, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Public Philosophy and Ethics (PPE) Program, 1988-1990 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Publication requests, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Publications, 1990-1993 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Puzzles, Undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Qualifying examination (QE) samples, 1971-1977 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Quine, Willard V.
    - General, 1947, 2001, 2006, undated (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Autobiography, Undated (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - "A Closer Look", Undated (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Empty domain, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - "Grades of Discriminability", 1976 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - "Intensions Revisted", 1977 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Quantification, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - "Reply to Professor Marcus", from The Ways of Paradox, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Schilpp, Paul, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Vitae, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - "What There Is" and notes, Undated (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Quine Persectives Conference, 1988-1989 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Quine symposium, Czech Republic, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Raffman, Diana, "Vagueness Without Paradox", 1994 January (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - "Recollections of Ernst Cassirer", 1996 October 2 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Recommendations, general, 1973-1974, undated (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Resnick, Michael, 1990, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - Restall, Greg, 2007 (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - Rockefeller Foundation
    - General, 1977-1981 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Bellagio Study and Conference Center, 1971-1974, 1989-1994 (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
  - Rorty, Richard, 1981-1985 (Box 32, Folder 4-5)
  - Rosenberg, Jay, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Russia, Academy of Sciences of the USSR Institute of Philosophy, "Modal and Intensional Logics (Bibliography)", 1983 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Ryger, Raphael S., articles, Circa 1962, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Salmon, Nathan, 1978, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Schock prize, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Scott, Dana, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Searle, John, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - "A Selective Bibliography of Philosophical Logic", 1975 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Sherman, Nancy, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Shklar, Judith, Undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Simposio Latino Americano de Logica Mathematica, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Skyrms, Brian, 1977, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 17-18)
  - Smith, Quentin, 1990-2000 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Soames, Scott
    - General, 1978-1998 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Kripke controversy, 2005-2007 (Box 32, Folder 21-23)
    - "Reference and Modality" lecture, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Soames, Scott and Quentin Smith, 1994-1998 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Society for Women in Philosophy (SWIP) Newsletter, 1979 September (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Speaking invitations, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - "Spinoza and the Ontological Proof", Circa 1986 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University
    - Job offer, 1980-1982 (Box 33, Folder 3-5)
    - Symposium, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Stern, H., 1997 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Substitutional quantification, 1968-1969, undated (Box 33, Folder 8-9)
  - Teacher evaluations, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Telephone charges fraud, 1986-1987 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Traditional logic, Undated (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Trajectories, 2006-2010 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Transcript of Quine and Marcus 1962 talk with copy from Logos, 1989, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 14-15)
  - Travel
    - Conferences, consulting, 1980, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - European trip, 1992, 1994, undated (Box 33, Folder 17-18)
    - Information on Crete, Undated (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Tufts University, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - "The Tyranny of the Yale Critics" by Colin Campbell, New York Times Magazine, 1986 February 9 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - "Uninformed Consent", 1979 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), 1993 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1990, 2008-2009 (Box 33, Folder 24-25)
  - University of California, Irvine, 1980-1982, 1992-1998 (Box 33, Folder 26-30)
  - University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA)
    - Ori Simchen notes on talk, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Philosophy Department review, 1986-1987 (Box 33, Folder 32-33)
  - University of California, Riverside, 1982-1983 (Box 33, Folder 34-35)
  - University of California, San Diego, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 36)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC)
    - Gift by anonymous donor, 2002 (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - Honorary degree, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle (UICC) news release, Undated (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - University of Massachusetts, 1976-1977, undated (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - University of North Carolina, Colloquium in Philosophy, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - University of Utah, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - University of Virginia report, Undated (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - Use and mention, New York Times puzzle example, 2000 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Vanderveken, Daniel, 1985-1988 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Veatch, Henry, 1972-1973 (Box 34, Folder 3-4)
  - Von Eckardt, Barbara, 1981-1983 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Von Staden, Heinrich, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Vuillemin, Jules, 1984-1985, 2001-2002 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - WGBH, "The Philosophy Project," Robert Nozick, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Weingartner, Paul, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - West, Cornel, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Western Washington University, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Who's Who, 1997-1998 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Wieckowski, Bartosz, 2008 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Wilbur Cross Medal, 1980, undated (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Wolf, Susan, "Moral Saints", Circa 1982 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Wolfson College, 1984-1993 (Box 34, Folder 16-18)
  - Wollheim, Donald, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Women, 1990-1991, undated (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - World Congress, 1981-1982 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Writings by others, 1969-1987, undated (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Yale University
    - General, 1982-1983 (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Advisory Committee, Department of Humanities, 1980-1981 (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Commencement, George W. Bush honorary degree, 2001 (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Faculty Handbook, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Faculty salaries, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - Public Philosophy and Ethics (PPE), 1988 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Yale University Press director search, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Zadeh, L. A., 1977 (Box 34, Folder 30)
- Departmental files, 1973-2008; Series III
  This series consists of files related to the Yale Philosophy Department during Ruth Barcan Marcus' tenure as a professor. The materials in the series consist of reports, meeting minutes, memoranda and notes pertaining to a variety of topics, including the recruitment, hiring and promotion of faculty, course curriculum, and administrative matters.
  Restricted until January 1, 2031.
  - General, 1973-1984 (Box 35, Folder 1-19)
  - General, 1984-2000, undated (Box 36, Folder 1-10)
  - Advisory Council, 1979-1983 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Allison, Henry, 1985-1986 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Blinder, David, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Carr, David, tenure issue, 1973-1981 (Box 36, Folder 14-16)
  - Cassirer-Heidegger issue, 1988-1993 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Chronicle of Higher Education rankings, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Courses
    - General, 1980-1982 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Course evaluations, 1976-1978, undated (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Professor Maull, Modern Philosophy, Undated (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Soames, Scott, Theories of Truth syllabi and notes, 1979-1980 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - da Costa, Emilia, 1976-1977, undated (Box 37, Folder 1-5)
  - Enrollment, Circa 1981, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Faculty evaluations, 1983 May (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Frankfurt, Harry, 1978-1996 (Box 37, Folder 8-10)
  - Graduate course requirements, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Graff, Hollace, 1974-1975 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Grünbaum, Adolf and Shelly Kagan correspondence, 2008 (Box 37, Folder 13)